

# Anton Vlasenko

E-mail § anton.vlacenko@gmail.com

Website § https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonvls

Phone § +380 (99) 052-52-15

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned Python developer with experience extracting, manipulating and storing large data streams with tools such as Pandas, Scikit Learn, NumPy, Airflow, Kafka. Possess strong linear algebra, statistical and probability theory background. Have several contributions to open source KNIME workflows and is an active Kaggle contributor. Certified Alteryx (SaaS) developer. Have extensive knowledge of pros and cons of well accepted Statistical / ML Techniques (Lin/Logit Regressions, Multivariate Regressions, Random Forests, XGBoost, LSTM, ARIMA). Have implemented ensembles of models and wrapped several state of the art Academic papers into Python. Contributed to DataRobot automated machine learning application by researching bias/variance trade off. Have built and documented several ETL processes with Airflow along with a combination of Celery + RabbitMQ.

### HARD SKILLS

- Python programming language (5 years), SQL (5 years)
- o Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Keras, PyTorch, Spark, TensorFlow
- o Alteryx, KNIME
- Customer Facing / Consulting / Dealing with C-level reps
- Development for cloud applications (AWS, Azure, GCP)
- AIrflow

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Wyzoo AUGUST - 2019 -- NOW

# Machine Learning Engineer

- Analyzed Large amounts of text and handwritten data by embracing Natural Language Processing. Have used Python NLTK, SpaCy, KNIME;
- Performed Image Recognition of Direct Mail Pieces of mail delivery giants (e.g. American Express). Have used TensorFlow, Keras, basic Python scripting;
- Assisted during the pre-sales process.

### RetargetApp

OCTOBER - 2018 -- AUG 2019

# Data Scientist / Data Engineer

- Built Data pipeline and data transition processes from the ground-up using AirFlow, Docker, Celery;
- Created the business health metrics system for the organization; took responsibility for each metric starting from Revenue ending by Cost Per Click for the target client. Used Tableau, AirFlow, Python/shell scripting;
- Created and deployed forecasting model for all the business attributes. Simple XGBoost implementation for Churned users prediction.

#### PROSAPIENT LTD

JULY - 2017 -- SEP 2018

# Data Engineer

- Calculating Churn, Retention, CAC, LTV, User Behavior
- Segmentation and clusterization of User Base
- Communicating findings in a straightforward and clean manner
- Designing and implementing data pipeline within existing infrastructure
- Web based project on python stack (Django, Redis, MongoDB, Docker, Postgres)
- Improving text recognition technology (NLTK/Spacy based)

#### DATAROBOT

# Data Analyst

- Business Automation (Python)
- Conduct Interviews with sales reps in order to gather and clean data to make better predictions
- Cleaning and shaping data sets
- Using Python (Pandas) and R to analyze data and uncover insights
- Apex, SalesForce
- Working alongside with CEO and Business Operations Vice President
- Solving Classification and Regression Problems (KNN, SVM, Naive Bayes, Custom ensemble models)

#### ITERA - RESEARCH

MAY - 2016 -- FEB - 2017

### Business Development Lead / BA

- Conducting Software Development contracts worldwide;
- Creating System Behaviour Description, SRS, Functional/Non-Functional requirements;
- Creating System Prototypes (Axure);
- Business Automation (using Python Scripts to parse and put together data);
- Organizes, maintains, and tracks sales data;
- Leading the department

## **EDUCATION**

### Zaporozhye National Technical University

• Master Degree at Computer Systems and Networks.